{
  "title": "Questions for G+12 and G+ Unlimited - Part 1",
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "Why are vibrators not used in piles concrete during casting for compaction?",
      "options": {
        "A": "concrete of pile is of high strength",
        "B": "compaction is not necessary in concrete",
        "C": "the concrete is of high slump and is self compacting",
        "D": "vibrators are not allowed"
      },
      "answer": "C"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "As per DM the most suitable technique for deep compaction used in Dubai is",
      "options": {
        "A": "soil removal",
        "B": "vertical drains",
        "C": "grouting",
        "D": "vibro compaction"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "Vibro compaction is the dynamic process used to reduce the volume of soil by",
      "options": {
        "A": "removing soil",
        "B": "replacing soil",
        "C": "adding stone columns",
        "D": "expelling air"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "The foundation in which a cantilever beam is provided to join 2 footing is called",
      "options": {
        "A": "strip footing",
        "B": "combined",
        "C": "raft",
        "D": "strap"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "Pile foundation is suitable for soils.",
      "options": {
        "A": "Soft rocky soil",
        "B": "compact soil",
        "C": "multi storey building",
        "D": "water logged soil"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "The compaction of concrete in the drilled pile hole is done by compressed air in case of",
      "options": {
        "A": "Franki pile",
        "B": "vibro pile",
        "C": "simplex pile",
        "D": "pressure pile"
      },
      "answer": "C"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "The minimum depth of foundation or footing in case of clay soil is",
      "options": {
        "A": "1m",
        "B": "0.7m",
        "C": "1.2m",
        "D": "0.9m"
      },
      "answer": "B"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "Generally the bearing capacity of granite is Kg/cm2",
      "options": {
        "A": "5-10",
        "B": "40-45",
        "C": "15-20",
        "D": "30-35"
      },
      "answer": "C"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "The form work including the props can be removed from beams minimum after days",
      "options": {
        "A": "3 days",
        "B": "7",
        "C": "21",
        "D": "14 days"
      },
      "answer": "B"
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "The pile which supports the load partly by friction and partly by resting on hard strata is",
      "options": {
        "A": "friction pile",
        "B": "bearing pile",
        "C": "rough pile",
        "D": "friction bearing pile"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 11,
      "question": "The function of the grouting in post tensioning tendons is to",
      "options": {
        "A": "Protect the tendons from corrosion",
        "B": "make the slab more strong",
        "C": "provide bond between tendons and the concrete",
        "D": "Both A and C are correct"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "question": "The minimum thickness of post tensioning slab is",
      "options": {
        "A": "15cm",
        "B": "120mm",
        "C": "300mm",
        "D": "20cm"
      },
      "answer": "B"
    },
    {
      "id": 13,
      "question": "The stressing of post tensioning cables in Dubai is done after days",
      "options": {
        "A": "3 days",
        "B": "10 days",
        "C": "21 days",
        "D": "7 days"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 14,
      "question": "The first layer of the block masonry in buildings walls should be",
      "options": {
        "A": "Thermal block",
        "B": "hollow blocks",
        "C": "ACC block",
        "D": "Solid blocks"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 15,
      "question": "The dewatering techniques used in Dubai for disposing water from construction site",
      "options": {
        "A": "Bypass",
        "B": "Flood control",
        "C": "deepwells",
        "D": "Both Wellpoint and deepwells"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 16,
      "question": "For non-cohesive soil like silty sand which dewatering technique is suitable?",
      "options": {
        "A": "deepwells",
        "B": "Flood control",
        "C": "Bypass",
        "D": "Well point system"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 17,
      "question": "In prestressed concrete beams, the loss is due to which of the following?",
      "options": {
        "A": "Elastic shortening",
        "B": "shrinkage of concrete",
        "C": "relaxation of steel",
        "D": "All"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 18,
      "question": "When the prestress is transferred to concrete in pre-tensioned concrete, the member shortens and the prestressing steel in it.",
      "options": {
        "A": "stressed",
        "B": "increase in length",
        "C": "remain same",
        "D": "shortens"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 19,
      "question": "The main purpose of providing pour strip in post tensioning slab in Dubai is",
      "options": {
        "A": "to stress tendons easily",
        "B": "to separate slabs",
        "C": "water flow",
        "D": "control elastic shortening"
      },
      "answer": "B"
    },
    {
      "id": 20,
      "question": "What is the value of poisson ratio for concrete of Pt slab?",
      "options": {
        "A": "0.3",
        "B": "0.4",
        "C": "0.25",
        "D": "0.2"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 21,
      "question": "The maximum allowable settlement in the raft foundation is",
      "options": {
        "A": "30mm",
        "B": "25mm",
        "C": "40mm",
        "D": "50mm"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 22,
      "question": "As the column height in RCC building increase, the reinforcement",
      "options": {
        "A": "increase",
        "B": "no change",
        "C": "size of column increase",
        "D": "decrease"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 23,
      "question": "In a 3 storey building, the live load of upper floors is taken by",
      "options": {
        "A": "beams and column of first floor",
        "B": "beams only",
        "C": "first slabs",
        "D": "column only"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 24,
      "question": "The final setting time of normal cement concrete is",
      "options": {
        "A": "5 hours",
        "B": "3 hours",
        "C": "7 hours",
        "D": "10 hours"
      },
      "answer": "C"
    },
    {
      "id": 25,
      "question": "The modulus of elasticity for concrete element is",
      "options": {
        "A": "4700xfc’",
        "B": "57000xfc’",
        "C": "5700x(fc’)0.5",
        "D": "4700x(fc’)0.5"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    }
  ]
}
